hey everybody
헤이 여러분!
it's Ariannita la Gringa and welcome back to my YouTube channel
Ariannita la Gringa예요. 제 유튜브 채널에 다시 와주셔서 환영해요.
in today's video I will teach you how to order food in a restaurant
오늘 영상에서는 식당에서 음식 주문하는 법을 알려드릴게요.
and to make this video I will actually go to a restaurant
그리고 이 영상을 찍기 위해 실제로 식당에 가볼 거예요.
this is a restaurant it's called Prime but what is a restaurant
여기가 식당인데, 이름은 Prime이에요. 그런데 '레스토랑'이 뭘까요?
a restaurant is a place where people go eat and drink
레스토랑은 사람들이 먹고 마시러 가는 곳이에요.
now there are many different types of restaurants but this one is
식당에는 여러 종류가 있는데, 이곳은
a fine dining restaurant which is basically a fancy restaurant
'파인 다이닝' 레스토랑이에요. 쉽게 말해 고급 레스토랑이죠.
and normally you'll dress up or wear formal apparel
보통 이런 곳엔 격식 있게 차려입고 가요.
people will normally wear formal attire or will get dressed up to go eat inside a restaurant
사람들은 대개 정장을 입거나 멋지게 차려입고 식당에 들어가 식사를 해요.
so right now I'm just wearing a bodysuit a black bodysuit a skirt and some heels
그래서 지금 저는 검은색 보디수트에 스커트, 그리고 힐을 신고 있어요.
and of course there are more kinds of different restaurants
물론 이 밖에도 다양한 종류의 식당이 있어요.
for example casual dining
예를 들면 '캐주얼 다이닝'이요.
this is a restaurant that offers a more relaxed atmosphere and simpler food
좀 더 편안한 분위기에 간단한 음식을 파는 식당이에요.
fast food this is a restaurant that serves food quickly and cheaply
'패스트푸드'는 음식을 빠르고 저렴하게 내주는 식당이고요.
this is a restaurant with an inexpensive and simple menu
저렴하고 간단한 메뉴를 파는 식당이죠.
and Cafe this is a restaurant that serves coffee pastries and light meals
그리고 '카페'는 커피와 페이스트리, 가벼운 식사를 파는 곳이에요.
now it's time to walk inside the restaurant let's go
이제 식당 안으로 들어가 볼 차례예요. 가볼까요!
when you walk inside the restaurant you'll be greeted by the host
식당에 들어가면 호스트가 맞아줘요.
this is the host and this is the host stand
이분이 호스트고, 여기가 호스트 스탠드예요.
so the host is the person that will greet you and will seat you at your table
그러니까 호스트는 여러분을 맞이하고 자리로 안내해 주는 사람이에요.
if it's busy you might have to wait in line but if you don't want to wait in line
붐비면 줄을 서서 기다려야 할 수도 있는데, 기다리기 싫다면
then you can book a reservation before heading to the restaurant
식당에 가기 전에 미리 예약을 하면 돼요.
a reservation is when you reserve a table
예약은 테이블을 미리 잡아두는 거예요.
that is a table over there
저기 보이는 게 테이블이에요.
and it makes sure you have a place to eat when you get to the restaurant
예약을 해두면 식당에 도착했을 때 앉을 자리가 확보돼요.
now I have a reservation so I'm going to talk to the host
저는 예약을 해놨으니 호스트에게 말을 걸어볼게요.
Hi how are you hi how you doing
안녕하세요, 잘 지내세요? -안녕하세요, 잘 지내시죠?
good how are you
네, 좋아요. 그쪽은요?
I have a reservation for 2 at 4:00 p.m. sure what was the name
오후 4시에 2명 예약했는데요. -네, 성함이 어떻게 되세요?
Ariana
아리아나요.
wonderful all righty I'll show you right this way
좋아요. 그럼 바로 이쪽으로 안내해 드릴게요.
thank you
감사합니다.
now what happens if you don't have your reservation
그런데 예약을 안 했으면 어떻게 될까요?
well this is how you can get a table
이렇게 하면 자리를 잡을 수 있어요.
hello how you doing good how are you doing
안녕하세요, 잘 지내세요? -네, 잘 지내요. 그쪽은요?
well thank you do you have a reservation with us today
잘 지내요, 감사합니다. 오늘 저희 쪽에 예약하셨나요?
no I don't do you guys have a table of course how many in your party
아니요, 안 했어요. 자리 있나요? -물론이죠. 일행이 몇 분이세요?
just two
딱 두 명이요.
when the host asks how many in your party they just
호스트가 "일행이 몇 분이세요?"라고 묻는 건
want to know how many people are coming to eat
그냥 몇 명이 식사하러 오는지 알고 싶어서예요.
perfect I'll show you right this way thanks
좋아요. 이쪽으로 안내해 드릴게요. -감사합니다.
enjoy thank you
맛있게 드세요. -감사합니다.
I am sitting at the table I was sitting over there but I asked the host if I can
지금 테이블에 앉아 있어요. 원래는 저쪽에 앉아 있었는데, 호스트한테
move to this table because there's better lighting for this video
이 영상 찍기에 조명이 더 좋아서 이 테이블로 옮겨도 되냐고 물어봤어요.
and the host gave me two menus this is a menu
그랬더니 호스트가 메뉴판을 두 개 줬어요. 이게 메뉴판이에요.
a menu is a list of food and drink items available at a restaurant
메뉴판은 식당에서 파는 음식과 음료 목록이에요.
now I will look through the menu to see what food I want to eat but as I look
이제 메뉴를 보면서 뭘 먹을지 고를 건데, 보는 동안
I will wait for the waitress or the waiter I'm not sure who it is
웨이트리스나 웨이터를 기다릴 거예요. 누가 올지는 모르겠어요.
he or she will introduce himself or herself
그 사람이 자기소개를 하고
and they will ask me what kind of beverage I will be drinking today
오늘 어떤 음료를 마실지 물어볼 거예요.
and he or she will ask me if I'm ready to order
그리고 주문할 준비가 됐는지도 물어봐요.
in America we call them waiters if they're men and waitresses if they're women
미국에서는 남자면 '웨이터', 여자면 '웨이트리스'라고 불러요.
a waiter or waitress is the person who takes your order and serves you food
웨이터나 웨이트리스는 주문을 받고 음식을 가져다주는 사람이에요.
hi my name is Gwen I'll be your server for tonight
안녕하세요, 저는 Gwen이고요. 오늘 저녁 담당 서버예요.
can I get you started with something to drink
먼저 마실 것부터 갖다드릴까요?
yeah I'll have a glass of water please sounds good I'll be right back with that
네, 물 한 잔 주세요. -좋아요. 금방 갖다드릴게요.
thank you
감사합니다.
thanks for the glass of water of course
물 갖다주셔서 감사해요. -천만에요.
after you sit down at the table then a server will come to you he or she will introduce themselves
테이블에 앉으면 서버가 다가와서 자기소개를 하고
and then they will ask if you would like a beverage or something to drink
음료나 마실 것을 원하는지 물어봐요.
so I just ordered a glass of water but honestly on the back of this menu you can find more
저는 그냥 물 한 잔만 시켰는데, 사실 이 메뉴판 뒷면에는 더 많은
beverages like fountain drinks cocktails etc
음료가 있어요. 탄산음료, 칵테일 같은 것들이요.
thanks for the glass of water of course are we ready to order
물 감사합니다. -천만에요. 주문하시겠어요?
I think I need more time
시간이 좀 더 필요할 것 같아요.
after the waiter or waitress comes back with your drink
웨이터나 웨이트리스가 음료를 가지고 돌아오면
then they will ask you if you're ready to order
주문할 준비가 됐는지 물어볼 거예요.
but if you're indecisive like me you might need more time looking at the menu
그런데 저처럼 우유부단하면 메뉴 보는 데 시간이 더 걸릴 수도 있어요.
now let's check out the menu this is the menu and
이제 메뉴를 한번 볼까요? 이게 메뉴판인데,
it has a list of different food options and drink options available at this restaurant
이 식당에서 주문할 수 있는 다양한 음식과 음료 목록이 있어요.
now typically a restaurant will have a physical menu
보통 식당에는 이런 실물 메뉴판이 있어요.
some restaurants right now you will scan a QR code from your phone
요즘 어떤 식당은 휴대폰으로 QR 코드를 스캔하면
and then you'll see the menu appear on your phone it won't be a physical copy like this menu
메뉴가 휴대폰에 떠요. 이런 실물 메뉴판이 아니라
it'll be a virtual copy
디지털 메뉴가 되는 거죠.
on the menu you can find appetizers entrees desserts and on the back of the menu beverages
메뉴판에는 전채(애피타이저), 메인 요리, 디저트가 있고, 뒷면에는 음료가 있어요.
this is a steakhouse as well as a seafood restaurant
여기는 스테이크 하우스이면서 해산물 식당이기도 해요.
so I'm going to order both steak and some seafood
그래서 스테이크랑 해산물을 둘 다 주문할 거예요.
while taking a look at the menu it's important to be aware if you have any food allergies
메뉴를 볼 때 음식 알레르기가 있는지 신경 쓰는 게 중요해요.
allergies are a medical condition where your body will react badly to certain ingredients
알레르기는 특정 성분에 몸이 안 좋게 반응하는 질환이에요.
for example if my friend is allergic to shrimp remember we're inside a seafood restaurant
예를 들어 제 친구가 새우 알레르기가 있다고 해볼게요. (여기 해산물 식당인 거 기억하세요.)
she has to be aware of what food is included or has shrimp on top of it
어떤 음식에 새우가 들어 있거나 위에 올라가 있는지 잘 살펴야 해요.
so basically she can't order anything that has shrimp
그러니까 새우가 들어간 건 아무것도 못 시켜요.
let me know down below if you guys have any food allergies
음식 알레르기가 있으면 댓글로 알려주세요.
and I personally don't have any food allergies
저는 개인적으로 음식 알레르기가 없어서
so I can order anything from this menu
이 메뉴에서 뭐든 주문할 수 있어요.
I will order a filet mignon
저는 안심 스테이크(필레미뇽)를 주문할 거예요.
and when you order the waitress will ask you how would you like it cooked
주문하면 웨이트리스가 "어떻게 익혀 드릴까요?"라고 물어봐요.
there are different ways to cook steak
스테이크 굽는 정도는 여러 가지가 있어요.
the first way is rare medium rare medium medium well and well done
레어, 미디엄 레어, 미디엄, 미디엄 웰, 웰던 순이에요.
I will order a filet mignon and I like it cooked medium well
저는 필레미뇽을 시킬 건데, 미디엄 웰로 익힌 걸 좋아해요.
I don't like it too raw or well done
너무 덜 익은 것도, 너무 바싹 익은 것도 안 좋아해요.
let me know down below how you guys like your steak cooked
여러분은 스테이크를 어떻게 익혀 먹는지 댓글로 알려주세요.
hi are we ready to order yeah so for my appetizer
안녕하세요, 주문하시겠어요? -네, 전채 요리로는
can I get some calamari and then for my entree I would like the 6 oz filet mignon
칼라마리(오징어튀김) 주시고요, 메인으로는 6온스 필레미뇽 주세요.
and how would you like that cooked can I get that medium well
어떻게 익혀 드릴까요? -미디엄 웰로 해주실 수 있어요?
okay and for your side
네, 사이드는요?
yeah can I get a side of mashed potatoes please
네, 매시드 포테이토 하나 주세요.
and do we want this all to come at once yes please thank you
다 한꺼번에 내드릴까요? -네, 부탁드려요. 감사합니다.
okay I'll go put that in right now thanks
네, 바로 주문 넣을게요. -감사해요!
I just ordered food from the waitress and I used some phrases to order food from the menu
방금 웨이트리스에게 음식을 주문했는데, 메뉴에서 주문할 때 몇 가지 표현을 썼어요.
I asked can I get some calamari and I would like a 6 oz filet mignon
"칼라마리 주세요(can I get some calamari)", "6온스 필레미뇽 주세요(I would like a 6 oz filet mignon)"라고 했죠.
but here are some more options and phrases to order food if you're inside a restaurant
식당에서 음식을 주문할 때 쓸 수 있는 표현이 더 있어요.
let's say you want to order some salmon
연어를 주문하고 싶다고 해볼게요.
some casual phrases to ask for this order include
편하게 주문할 때 쓰는 표현으로는
I'd like some salmon can I get salmon please
"I'd like some salmon", "can I get salmon please" 같은 게 있어요.
I will have salmon thanks
"I will have salmon, thanks(연어로 할게요)."
but if you want to sound more formal you can say
좀 더 격식 있게 말하고 싶으면 이렇게 할 수 있어요.
may I get some salmon please I'd like to order salmon
"may I get some salmon please", "I'd like to order salmon",
and could I get some salmon please
그리고 "could I get some salmon please"요.
meanwhile I wait for my food let's see what's on the table
음식을 기다리는 동안, 테이블 위에 뭐가 있는지 살펴볼게요.
this is the table and on the table there is a tablecloth
이게 테이블이고, 테이블 위에는 식탁보가 깔려 있어요.
it's a black tablecloth and then on the table this is a napkin
검은색 식탁보고요, 테이블 위에 이건 냅킨이에요.
and before you eat you'll normally put this on your lap because if food spills on your lap
식사 전에 보통 이걸 무릎 위에 올려둬요. 음식이 무릎에 쏟아져도
you don't want it falling on your clothes
옷에 떨어지면 안 되니까요.
and in front of me this is a wine glass
그리고 제 앞에 있는 이건 와인 잔이에요.
I'm not drinking wine because I'm just drinking water
저는 와인을 안 마시고 그냥 물만 마시고 있어요.
and then I have silverware or you can also call these utensils
그리고 은식기(silverware)가 있는데, 이걸 '식기(utensils)'라고도 불러요.
silverware or utensils include a fork a knife and a spoon
은식기, 즉 식기에는 포크, 나이프, 스푼이 있어요.
and normally these will be inside a napkin but they're just laid out flat on the table
보통은 냅킨 안에 들어 있는데, 여기선 그냥 테이블 위에 펼쳐져 있네요.
now what's the difference between silverware and utensils
그럼 'silverware'와 'utensils'의 차이가 뭘까요?
silverware are eating utensils made of silver these are silverware
'silverware'는 은으로 만든 식기를 말해요. 이게 silverware죠.
utensils include forks spoons knives chopsticks etc
'utensils'에는 포크, 숟가락, 칼, 젓가락 등이 다 들어가요.
even if they're made of plastic wood or other materials
플라스틱이나 나무, 다른 재료로 만들어졌어도 다 식기예요.
thank you so much you're welcome
정말 감사합니다! -천만에요.
there we are thank you
자, 나왔습니다. -감사합니다.
you're welcome everything looks delicious
천만에요. -다 맛있어 보여요.
is there anything else I can grab for you maybe just a refill of water please
더 필요한 거 있으세요? -물만 좀 더 채워주세요.
I'll go get that right now thank you
지금 바로 갖다드릴게요. -감사합니다.
thank you so much you're welcome
정말 감사합니다. -천만에요.
I just got my food on the table so I ordered some calamari as my appetizer
방금 음식이 테이블에 나왔어요. 전채로 칼라마리를 시켰는데,
so normally with an appetizer you'll get that before your main dish before your entree
보통 전채는 메인 요리(앙트레)보다 먼저 나와요.
but I wanted everything together because I'm really hungry
그런데 저는 너무 배고파서 다 같이 달라고 했어요.
and then for my entree I ordered a 6 oz filet mignon that is medium well
그리고 메인으로는 미디엄 웰로 익힌 6온스 필레미뇽을 시켰고요.
and then I also ordered a side dish of mashed potatoes
사이드로 매시드 포테이토도 하나 시켰어요.
also if you're indecisive and you don't know what to order you can ask the server
그리고 우유부단해서 뭘 시킬지 모르겠으면 서버에게 물어봐도 돼요.
when she takes your order what do you recommend
주문 받을 때 "뭐 추천해 주세요?(what do you recommend?)"
or what's your favorite dish on the menu
또는 "메뉴에서 제일 좋아하는 게 뭐예요?(what's your favorite dish?)"라고요.
if you need something while you're eating
식사 중에 뭔가 필요하면,
for example a refill of water some more sauce
예를 들어 물 리필이나 소스 추가,
or anything with your food you can call your waiter's attention
음식 관련해서 뭐든 필요하면 웨이터를 부르면 돼요.
for example you can wave your hand politely and say excuse me or excuse me sir
예를 들어 정중하게 손을 들고 "excuse me" 또는 "excuse me sir"라고 하면 돼요.
and that will call their attention and they will assist you if you need any help
그러면 웨이터의 주의를 끌 수 있고, 도움이 필요하면 도와줄 거예요.
I just finished my food and everything was delicious
방금 식사를 다 했는데, 다 맛있었어요.
now if you're not a big fan of meat like steak or animal products
그런데 스테이크 같은 고기나 동물성 식품을 별로 안 좋아한다면
you might be vegetarian or a vegan
'베지테리언'이나 '비건'일 수도 있어요.
now what's the difference between these two terms
그럼 이 두 용어의 차이는 뭘까요?
vegetarian food is a type of food that does not include any meat
'베지테리언(채식)' 음식은 고기가 전혀 안 들어간 음식이에요.
vegan food is any food that doesn't include any meats and any other products that comes from
'비건' 음식은 고기는 물론, 동물에서 나오는 어떤 제품도 안 들어간 음식이에요.
animals like eggs dairy and even honey
달걀, 유제품, 심지어 꿀까지요.
can I clear some of this stuff out of the way yes please I'm finished thank you
이거 좀 치워드려도 될까요? -네, 부탁해요. 다 먹었어요. 감사합니다.
okay
좋아요.
and then can I also get a refill of some more water
그리고 물도 좀 더 채워주실 수 있어요?
of course thanks
물론이죠. -감사합니다.
thank you so much you're welcome did we want to box for this one
정말 감사합니다. -천만에요. 이거 포장해 드릴까요?
yes please
네, 부탁해요.
here's that boxed up for you thank you
여기 포장해 드렸어요. -감사합니다.
now what happens if you don't finish eating all of your food like I did
저처럼 음식을 다 못 먹으면 어떻게 할까요?
I had some leftover mashed potatoes well you can take your food to go and it comes in a box
매시드 포테이토가 좀 남았는데요, 이럴 땐 음식을 포장해서 가져갈 수 있어요. 상자에 담아주죠.
so these mashed potatoes will be my leftovers for tomorrow
그래서 이 매시드 포테이토는 내일 먹을 남은 음식이 될 거예요.
and would you guys like the check yes please can I get the check
계산서 드릴까요? -네, 계산서 주시겠어요?
thanks yes thank you so much and I have my card here so I'll just give it to you now
정말 감사합니다. 카드 여기 있으니까 지금 바로 드릴게요.
thank you thank you
감사합니다, 감사합니다.
thank you so much
정말 감사합니다.
when you're ready to leave the restaurant you will need to pay the check or the bill
식당을 나갈 준비가 되면 계산서(check 또는 bill)를 지불해야 해요.
so this is the bill and it has the total cost of your meal
이게 계산서인데, 식사 총액이 적혀 있어요.
and then you will pay with a credit card or cash
그리고 신용카드나 현금으로 결제하면 돼요.
another way to pay for your meal is by splitting the bill with someone
식사비를 내는 또 다른 방법은 계산서를 다른 사람과 나눠 내는 거예요.
so if you want to divide the bill between you and another person
나랑 다른 사람이 계산서를 나눠 내고 싶으면
that means you will split the bill in half
계산서를 반으로 나누는 거죠.
so you can ask the waiter excuse me can you split the bill that way
그럼 웨이터한테 "실례지만 계산서 반반으로 나눠주실 수 있어요?"라고 물어보면 돼요.
for example instead of paying $50 you and your friend will only spend $25 per person
예를 들어 50달러를 혼자 내는 대신, 친구랑 각자 25달러씩만 내는 거예요.
I just paid my check or my bill and right now this is my receipt that I paid for it
방금 계산서를 냈고요, 지금 이게 제가 결제한 영수증이에요.
also in the US waiters and waitresses rely on a heavy portion of tipping as their pay
그리고 미국에서는 웨이터와 웨이트리스가 수입의 상당 부분을 팁에 의존해요.
so if you eat inside a restaurant with a waiter or waitress that is providing you a service
그러니 서버가 서빙해 주는 식당에서 식사한다면
you should tip at least 20% of the bill to pay the waiter
웨이터에게 계산 금액의 최소 20%는 팁으로 줘야 해요.
or waitress for their work
그분들이 한 일에 대한 보답으로요.
what happens if I don't want to pay a tip
팁을 주고 싶지 않으면 어떻게 될까요?
well here in America it's very common to pay for your tip
미국에서는 팁을 주는 게 아주 일반적이에요.
because the waitress or waiter is providing a service for you
웨이트리스나 웨이터가 여러분에게 서비스를 제공하니까요.
even if you didn't like your food if you think it was too spicy
음식이 마음에 안 들었어도, 너무 맵다고 느꼈어도,
or if you just didn't like it at all it's common to leave a tip
아예 별로였어도 팁은 남기는 게 보통이에요.
because that is very polite
그게 아주 예의 바른 행동이거든요.
if you don't leave a tip that could be considered rude and impolite
팁을 안 남기면 무례하고 예의 없다고 여겨질 수 있어요.
so remember if you're eating inside a restaurant
그러니 기억하세요. 식당 안에서 식사한다면,
if you're dining in don't forget to leave a tip
매장에서 먹는 거라면 팁 남기는 걸 잊지 마세요.
there are two ways to give a tip
팁을 주는 방법은 두 가지예요.
since I already paid with a credit card
저는 이미 신용카드로 결제했으니까
I can just leave the tip amount right here and then I will add up the total right here
여기에 팁 금액을 적고, 여기에 총액을 합산하면 돼요.
but another way is just to leave a cash tip
또 다른 방법은 그냥 현금으로 팁을 남기는 거예요.
so since I already have cash I'll just leave a cash tip
저는 현금이 있으니 그냥 현금 팁을 남길게요.
I just paid for my meal and I tipped but before leaving the restaurant
방금 식사비를 내고 팁도 줬어요. 그런데 식당을 나가기 전에
I want to show you some more parts of this restaurant
이 식당의 다른 곳도 좀 더 보여드릴게요.
when I first entered I was greeted by the host and then he led me to my table where the waitress
처음 들어왔을 때 호스트가 맞아줬고, 그다음 제 테이블로 안내해 줬어요. 거기서 웨이트리스가
asked me if I wanted anything to eat
뭘 드시겠냐고 물어봤죠.
in this restaurant there is a bar behind me is the bar
이 식당에는 바(bar)가 있어요. 제 뒤에 있는 게 바예요.
and it's a place where people serve drinks
사람들이 음료를 만들어 내주는 곳이죠.
and the person that serves drinks is called the bartender
그리고 음료를 서빙하는 사람을 '바텐더'라고 해요.
he's the person that mixes and serves drinks
음료를 섞어서 내주는 사람이에요.
and then the person that helps out the bartender is called the barback
그리고 바텐더를 돕는 사람을 '바백(barback)'이라고 해요.
he's basically like the assistant where he helps keep everything organized and also helps with serving drinks
쉽게 말해 보조인데, 모든 걸 정리하고 음료 서빙도 도와줘요.
and of course
그리고 물론,
this restaurant has a restroom
이 식당에는 화장실도 있어요.
so if you're a man you will use the gents restroom
남자라면 남자 화장실을 쓰고,
and if you're a woman you will use the ladies restroom
여자라면 여자 화장실을 쓰면 돼요.
and behind me this is the dining area
그리고 제 뒤에는 식사 공간이 있어요.
so this is where the host will seat you at one of these tables
호스트가 이 테이블들 중 하나로 여러분을 안내해 주는 곳이죠.
also behind me you can see some servers
그리고 제 뒤로 서버들도 보이는데,
called waitresses or waiters who will help serve you food
웨이트리스나 웨이터라고 부르고, 음식 서빙을 도와줘요.
also when you leave there might be some extra plates
또 손님이 나갈 때 테이블에 접시나
or silverware on the table and that's where the bus boy
은식기가 남아 있을 수 있는데, 그럴 때 '버스 보이'
or bus girl will help clear the table and set up a new table
또는 '버스 걸'이 테이블을 치우고 새로 세팅해 줘요.
for the next couple or family who want to eat at a table
다음에 식사할 손님이나 가족을 위해서요.
and of course every restaurant will have a kitchen
그리고 물론 모든 식당에는 주방이 있어요.
behind me this is the kitchen and in the kitchen you will
제 뒤가 주방인데, 주방에는
have a chef who will prepare delicious food
맛있는 음식을 만들어 줄 셰프가 있어요.
my food was amazing also there are many more chefs like the head chef a sous chef
제 음식 정말 훌륭했어요. 그리고 헤드 셰프, 수셰프 등 셰프가 더 많이 있고요.
you'll also have someone doing the dishes
설거지를 담당하는 사람도 있고,
and then someone to bring the food out to the tables that's called a food runner
음식을 테이블로 가져다주는 사람도 있는데, 그걸 '푸드 러너'라고 해요.
I just ate inside the restaurant but this restaurant also has a patio
저는 식당 안에서 먹었는데, 이 식당에는 테라스(파티오)도 있어요.
this is a patio and it's a nice place to eat outside when the
여기가 테라스인데, 야외에서 식사하기 좋은 곳이에요.
weather is really warm like in the summer
여름처럼 날씨가 따뜻할 때요.
okay everybody that's all for today's video about restaurant vocabulary
자 여러분, 오늘 레스토랑 어휘 영상은 여기까지예요.
now you guys are ready to tackle any menu
이제 여러분은 어떤 메뉴든 자신 있게 주문할 수 있을 거예요.
go ahead and give me a like subscribe
좋아요와 구독 눌러주시고,
and remember keep practicing your English every day
매일 영어 연습하는 거 잊지 마세요.
and I'll see you guys next week
다음 주에 또 만나요.
bye
안녕!